Anders G. Nordby



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Systems Architect and Senior Developer with 20+ years of experience designing scalable software solutions across industries. Specialized in application security, distributed systems, and modern architecture. Proven leader in team coordination, agile practices, and security governance.

WORK EXPERIENCE

05/2019 - PRESENT

Delichon AS

Systems Architect & Senior Developer

Customer: Element Logic **Duration:** 5 years

Roles: Senior Systems Developer, Security Champion

Technologies: C#, Akka.NET, Blazor, REST, GraphQL, NHibernate, SQL, NUnit, Moq, Microsoft .NET Standard, ASP.NET, TeamCity, Octopus Deploy, Git, Powershell, Kiuwan.

Responsibility: Senior developer on Element Logic's main product, eManager. Additionally, focuses on application security, and is the initiator and leader for Element Logic's Security Chapions Guild.

Customer: ABB

Role: Senior systemutvikler **Duration:** 6 months

Technologies: Azure DevOps, Azure DB, Azure WebServices, Akka.NET, TypeScript, React JS, C#, Microsoft .NET Core, TFS, Git, Powershell.

01/2018 - 04/2019

Sopra Steria

Lead Software Engineer

Roles: In-house architect responsible for planning and QA of offers to customers. Senior developer for some customers.

Customers: Skatteetaten, Helsedirektoratet.

Technologies: C#, .Net, Episerver CMS, ASP.NET MVC, Microsoft SQL Server, JavaScript, Jira, Confluence, TFS, Git.

03/2014 - 08/2017

CGI

Senior Web Developer

Roles: Team-leder, scrum master, hands-on architect.

Customers: ASKO, Fellesforbundet, Tekna, PIA, Miljødirektoratet. **Technologies:** C#, inRiver PIM, Apptus eSales, Episerver CMS, Episerver Commerce, IdentityServer, T-SQL, NServiceBus, Jira, Confluence, jMeter, BlazeMeter, Angular.js, Knockout.js.

03/2010 - 01/2014 08/2008 - 12/2009 02/2006 - 07/2008 10/2004 - 02/2008

05/1995 - 06/2002

Making Waves, Senior Systems Consultant Creuna, Consultant / Systems Developer Ocelluz, Systems Developer & Project Manager Anders Nordby Konsulenttjenester Ajilon, Consultant https://www.linkedin.com/in/agnordby/

(+47) 932 20 333

anders@delichon.no

Updated version of this dokument: https://github.com/agnordby/cv

Barcelona (One week pr month in Oslo)

KEY COMPETENCIES

Processes

Systemarkitektur, Scrum, Kanban, prosjektledelse.

Development

C#, Akka.Net, GraphQL, NHibernate, Blazor, Gherkin, Specflow, Cypress, NUnit, Moq, DoxFx, Docker, Swagger, Kiuwan, PowerBI, log4net, Episerver, ASP.Net, T-SQL, PL/SQL, Javascript, JSON, NServiceBus, REST, WebAPI, XML, HTML, CSS, Powershell, LATEX.

Tool

Jira, Confluence, TeamCity, Octopus Deploy, Git, TFS, SubVersion, NewRelic, jMeter, BlazeMeter, NuGet, Kiuwan.

CERTIFICATIONS

2021 Certified Optimizely Developer
 2020 Microsoft Azure Fundamentals
 2019 PRINCE2 Practitioner
 2019 Certified Scrum Master
 2018 PRINCE2 Foundation

COURSES

Building an AppSec Scanning Programme
 Tom Gilb: Architecture Workshop
 Sopra Steria: Arkitekturskolen
 Microsoft: Lead Enterprise Architect Programme

EDUCATION

2003 – 2004 University of Oslo, Teacher Training
 1999 – 2000 Oslo Business Academy, IT Candidate
 1987 – 1996 University of Oslo, Cand.Mag.
 1984 – 1987 Eikeli High School, Natural Sciences

AWARDS

2013-2017 Episerver Most Valued Professional

LANGUAGES

EXCELLENT Norwegian (native), English
INTERMEDIATE Bulgarian, German
BEGINNER Spanish, Japanese